Thomas Cook Brown Papers
Thomas Cook Brown Papers
1929-1966
Brown, Thomas Cook.
8 linear ft.
Papers of the American journalist, editorial writer for the Buffalo Courier-Express (1891-1967). Collection includes correspondence (1930-1966); clippings, writings, photographs, and scrapbooks. Writings consist of Brown's column 'Retrospect' and editorials for the Buffalo Courier-Express (1929-1965).
148873
Biographical History
Thomas Cook Brown was an American journalist, editorial writer for the Buffalo (New York) Courier-Express, and a member of the National Conference of Editorial Writers. In 1957 he received the Trinity College Alumni Medal of Excellence; he also received the Golden Cross of the Order of the Phoenix in 1963 for his involvement in Greek-American relations.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Thomas Cook Brown Papers consist of correspondence, writings, printed material and memorabilia (clippings, photographs, scrapbooks, and similar items). The collection is divided into eight series.
Correspondence covers the years 1930-1966.
Miscellany contains writings by others including Brown's students in his writing class, a few telegrams, and assorted other items.
News clippings relate to both Brown and others, followed by a few Photographs.
Printed material and Published material (as well as some of the correspondence from the 1940s and 1950s) reflect Brown's interest in the Justice for Greece Committee, the English Speaking Union, and the Atlantic Union Committe, Inc. He also maintained his ties with both his alma maters, Deveaux School and Trinity College.
Scrapbooks contain letters of commendation for his column, news clippings (particularly of World War II), and samples of his columns and editorials. These books reflect the general content of the collection.
Writings contains holograph (handwritten) manuscripts, published and page proofs (articles, Brown's "Retrospect" column, editorials, and an interview), and typescripts of essays, interviews and speeches.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged chronologically. Writings are subdivided alphabetically by type (articles, columns, etc) and within that arranged chronologically.
Related Material
has numerous collections relating to journalism, including the papers of noted journalists such as Erskine Caldwell, Bob Considine, Marguerite Higgins, Cecilia "Jackie" Martin, William Safire, Dorothy Thompson, and many others. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Journalism; New York State; Brown, Thomas Cook -- Archives.; Buffalo courier-express (Buffalo, N.Y.); Journalism.; Journalists -- United States.; Newspapers -- Sections, columns, etc. -- Editorials.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Editorials.; Newspaper columns.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Journalists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Brown, 1967-1968.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - 1930, 1932, 1934-1966, 31 folders (Box 1)
  - Undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Miscellany
  - General (Box 1)
  - Typescripts
    - Papers by students and others, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Speeches by others, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Telegrams (Box 1)
- News clippings
  - Brown (Box 1)
  - Others, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Others, 9 folders (Box 2)
- Photographs
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
- Printed material
  - Miscellaneous, 9 folders (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 3)
- Published material
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
- Scrapbooks
  - Miscellaneous, 2 volumes (Oversize 1)
- Writings
  - Holographs
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Published and page proofs
    - Articles (Box 3)
    - Column, "Retrospect"
      - 1930-1939, 10 folders (Box 3)
      - 1940-1943, 19 folders (Box 4)
      - 1942-1951, 22 folders (Box 5)
      - 1951-1959, 7 folders (Box 6)
      - Undated, 7 folders (Box 6)
    - Editorials
      - 1929-1930, 1935-1938, 1940, 1943-1950, 15 folders (Box 6)
      - 1951-1965, 15 folders (Box 7)
      - Undated, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Interview (Box 7)
  - Typescripts
    - Essays, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Interview (Box 7)
    - Speeches, 2 folders (Box 7)